{"data":[{"question":"I'm going to _____ some work.","a":"make","b":"do","c":"made","d":"did","answer":"2","explain":"\n- We use the verb 'do' when someone performs an action, activity or task \n- Going to + Verb infinitive","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"The carpenter is _____ a chair.","a":"doing","b":"make","c":"made","d":"making","answer":"4","explain":"\n- We use the verb 'make' for constructing, building or creating \n- Be + V_ing: Continous tense","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"She _____ several mistakes in the dictation.","a":"make","b":"made","c":"did","d":"do","answer":"2","explain":"\n- We use the verb 'make' for constructing, building or creating\n- Simple past tense: make-> made","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"What are you _____, Carol? \"Nothing.\"","a":"make","b":"doing","c":"made","d":"done","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Use the verb 'do' when speaking about things in general: to describe an action without saying exactly what the action is \n- This form is often used with the words 'something, nothing, anything, everything, etc \n- Be+ V_ing: Continuous tense","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"Why don't you ______ an effort?","a":"do","b":"made","c":"make","d":"did","answer":"3","explain":"\n- There are a number of standard expressions that take the verb 'make'\nEx: Make an effort; make a mess...\n- Don't + Verb infinitive","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"I'll ______ my duty.","a":"make","b":"do","c":"have","d":"done","answer":"2","explain":"\n- 'Do' is often used when referring to work of any kind \n- Simple Future tense: Will\/shall + Verb infinitive","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"He is _____ a lot of money.","a":"doing","b":"having","c":"making","d":"made","answer":"3","explain":"\n- There are a number of standard expressions that take the verb 'make' \nEx: make a profit; make money... \n- Be + V_ing: Continuous tense","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"Why don't you ______ an effort?","a":"make","b":"made","c":"done","d":"do","answer":"1","explain":"\n- There are a number of standard expressions that take the verb 'make' .Ex: make a profit; make money... \n- Don't + Verb infinitive ","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"Mary, ______ me a favour!","a":"make","b":"do","c":"does","d":"made","answer":"2","explain":"\n- There are a number of standard expressions that take the verb \"do\"\nEx: Do a favour, do business...\n- Don't + Verb infinitive","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"},{"question":"We are going to ______ a journey.","a":"do","b":"make","c":"made","d":"did","answer":"2","explain":"\n- There are a number of standard expressions that take the verb \"make\" .Ex: Make a journey, make a profit... \n- Going to + Verb infinitive ","category":"3","subcategorylv1":"10","subcategorylv2":"4","type":"1"}]}